Guide to the Everett Franklin Phillips papers, 1868-1950.
Phillips, Everett Franklin papers, 1868-1950.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Everett Franklin Phillips papers, 1868-1950.
21-23-768
Everett Franklin Phillips, 1878-1951.
4.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, and other papers relating to bees and beekeeping.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Apiculture, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports, and other papers relating to bees and beekeeping. Includes material on the manufacture, patent assignment, alleged patent infringement, and use of royalties of the product made by the Dyce Honey Process; on Nellie J. Stratton's development of a honey and lactose candy; on the coordination of entomologists' research efforts during World War II; on the establishment and growth of the Charles C. Miller Memorial Library; and of the publication of beekeeping journals, pamphlets, and books.
Additional papers include correspondence with other apiologists and entomologists concerning the behavior and raising of bees and improved methods for producing and shipping honey, with the A.I. Root Company of Medina, Ohio, producers of beekeepers' supplies and honey and publishers of Gleanings in Bee Culture, with editors of the American Bee Journal, and with U.S. Representatives Gilbert N. Haugen, Franklin Menges, William L. Nelson, and Gale H. Stalker and Senators Robert F. Wagner, Sr., concerning the opposition of American honey interests to bills (1928, 1930) designed to allow the addition of corn sugars to manufactured products without marking this addition on the label; together with an unpublished ms. by Phillips on the behavior of bees and photograph concerning beekeeping.
Also includes correspondence, 1868-1888; petition relating to adulteration of honey, 1878, and one Japanese fable presented by Marice G. Dadant to Dr. Phillips, 1948, selected by C. P. Dadant and Charles Dadant, previously located in Mann Library, Cornell University.
Correspondents include Charles P. Alexander, Percy N. Annand, Liberty Hyde Bailey, Camille Pierre Dadant, Elton J. Dyce, Livingston Farrand,Albert R. Mann, James G. Needham, Charles E. Palm, Sherman Peer, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Ernest H. Root, Huber H. Root, Nellie J. Stratton, Henry A. Wallace, Sherman Whitney, and many others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Phillips, Everett Franklin, 1878-1951.; Alexander, Charles P. (Charles Paul), 1889-1981.; Annand, Percy N.; Bailey, L. H. (Liberty Hyde), 1858-1954.; Dadant, C. P. (Camille Pierre), 1851-1938.; Dadant, Charles.; Dyce, Elton J.; Farrand, Livingston, 1867-1939.; Mann, Albert Russell, 1880-1947.; Needham, James G. (James George), 1868-1956.; Palm, Charles E.; Peer, Sherman.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Root, Ernest H.; Root, H. H. (Huber H.); Stratton, Nellie J.; Wallace, Henry A.; Whitney, Sherman.; Charles C. Miller Memorial Library.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Entomology.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Law and legislation.; Bee culture.; Bee culture--Study and teaching.; Beekeepers.; Candy.; Entomologists.; Entomology.; Entomology--Study and teaching.; Honey.; Honey--Law and legislation.
Form and Genre Terms:
Patents.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Anderson, John, 1926-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Armbruster, Ludwig, 1924-1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bee Products Marketing Agreement, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Benton, Frank, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Casteel, D.B., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Casteel, D.B. - Behavior, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dadant, C.P. - American Bee Journal, Hamilton, Illinois, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dadant, C.P., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dadant, C.P., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dadant, C.P., 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dadant, C.P., 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dadant, L.C., 1926-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dadant, Maurice, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Davis, J.J., 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Davis, J.J., 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Davis, J.J., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Davis, J.J., 1928 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Demuth, George S., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Demuth, George S., 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Demuth, George S., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - Demuth, George S., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Demuth, George S., 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Demuth, George S., 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Demuth, George S., 1928 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - Demuth, George S., 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Demuth, George S., 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Demuth, George S., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Demuth, George S., 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Demuth, George S., 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Demuth, George S., 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Demuth, George S. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Detwiler, John Y., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Dodge, Parker, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Doolittle, Gilbert M., 1918 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dyce, Elton J., 1925-1930 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Dyce, Elton J., 1925-1931 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Dyce, Elton J., 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Dyce, Elton J., 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Dyce, Elton J., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Dyce, Elton J., 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Dyce, Elton J., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
  - Dyce, Elton J. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Dyce, Elton J., 1927-1932 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 49-50)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 53-54)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Dyce, Elton J. and W.E. Dunham, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - D - E bee correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - D - E bee correspondence, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 60-61)
  - D - E bee correspondence, 1938-39 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - D - E bee correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Farrar, Clarence L., 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Farrar, Clarence L., 1926-1929 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Farrar, Clarence L., 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 66-67)
  - Gilman, A., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Gould, A.C., 1925-1929 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Gould, A.C., 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Gould, A.C., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Gould, A.C., 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 72-73)
  - Gould, A.C., 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 74-75)
  - Gould, A.C. (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 77-78)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 79-80)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 82-83)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 84-86)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Hambleton, James I., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Hambleton, James I. (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Hopkins, Isaac, 1914-1925 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Kalfus, Peter, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Lundie, A.E., 1924-1931 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - McCubbin, J.C. - article: "The Rambler", 1920 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Miller, F. Eric, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Miller, Charles C., 1906-1914 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miller, Charles C. news clippings, 1923; 1943 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Milum, V.G., 1924-1934 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Paddock, F.B., 1924-1931 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Pellett, Frank C., 1924-1931 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Phillips, Everett F. - Apis Club, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Phillips, Everett F. - Beekeeping Library, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Rayment, Tarlton, 1926-1937 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Rea, George H., 1926-1931 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1905-1906 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1909-1912 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1913 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1914 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1915 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1916 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1917 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1918 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1919 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1921 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1922 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1926 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1927-1931 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1934-1936; 1942 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Root (A.I.) Co., 1934-1950 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Root (A.I.) Co. (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Root, E.R. (A.I. Root Co.), 1919 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Root, E.R. (A.I. Root Co.), 1926-1928 (Box 2, Folder 51-52)
  - Root, E.R. (A.I. Root Co.), 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Root, E.R. (A.I. Root Co.), 1928-1931 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - Root, E.R. (A.I. Root Co.), 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
  - Root, E.R. (A.I. Root Co.), 1926-1934 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Snodgras, R.E., 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Stewart, Charles - European foulbrood, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sturges, Arthur P., 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sturtevant, Arnold P., 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Vaillancourt, C., 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Watson, Lloyd R., 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Wilson, H.F., 1924-1926 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1939-1947 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Papers and reports
  - Miscellaneous documents pertaining to the drafting and enactment of the law to regulate importation of adult honeybees into the United States, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "History of fight against corn sugar interests in the United States", 1926-1930 (Box 3, Folder 18-20)
  - Office of Defense Transportation and Office of Price Administration, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - War Production Board circulars, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - USDA leaflets, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Canada - Wartime Prices and Trade Board, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Zoology as an Applied Science, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Temperature and Wintering of Bees, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The Present Opportunity in Beekeeping, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Recent Investigations on Bee Diseases, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Papers on persons concerned with bees and beekeeping: Aristotle, presented by Paul Needham; Johannes Dzierson, presented by Everett Oertel; F.W.L. Sladen, presented by E.F. Phillips; A.J. Cook, presented by R.B. Wilsob; G.M. Doolittle, presented by A.C. Gould; John S. Harabison, presented by R.L. Parker, 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Frank C. Pellett, naturalist: brochure (with picture) on lectures given by him on Chautauqua Circuit (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Julius Robert Hoffman, commercial beekeeper: biographical sketch, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Program for first short course in beekeeping, Cornell University, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - The Contact of Apiculture with the Basic Sciences, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Information on effect of altitude on nectar secretion by Phillips, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Reports on Occurrence of Brood Diseases of Bees and Activities in Inspection Work, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence with R.F. Remer, Sioux Honey Assn., Sioux City, Iowa, concerning: manufacture of honey under Dyce process by Sioux Honey Assn.; problems of cooperatives for handling honey; release of honey from price regulations. Also correspondence with E.J. Dyce, W.J. Dedicott, S.F. Wadden, Allan H. Treman, G.F. Rogalsky, 1940-1950 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence on patent infringements on Dyce Process with Lloyd B. Sherman, V.V. Dexter, Sherman Whitney, C.E. Hamann. Comparison of Lund and Dyce honey processes. Copy of contract with Honey Butter Products Corp. Also correspondence with J.J.C. Downey, G.F. Rogalsky, D.B. Bradshaw, Sherman Peer, L.N. Simmons, Seth J. Shaw (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Nellie J. Stratton, 1928-1946 (Box 3, Folder 38-40)
    Correspondence and reports re development of a honey and lactose candy by Miss Stratton. Mr. James Collins, Blue Moon Cheese Products Co., Messrs. S.F. Whitman and Sons, W. E. Bliss, Pres. The Honey Candy Co. of America, L.A. Beeghley (re patents), Karl Fenning (re Patent), S. Erison, The Honey Candy Co. of America, Fred C. Taylor, The Sugar Institute, Inc., W. Guthrie, Truscon Steel Co., H.P. Weld, Dept. of Psychology, Cornell University
  - Mr. Rapheal Gould, American Library Service: re Frans Blom and Edwin C. Alphonsus ms. on beekeeping in Maya civilization (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Questions based on A.B. Comstock's book "How to Keep Bees" for use in correspondence course given by Dr. Burton N. Gates, Massachusettes Ag. College. Also questions based on Phillips' book "Beekeeping" (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence re obtaining material on John S. Harbison: Mrs. M.J. Harbison, Mrs. John S. Harbison, Mrs. John C. Taggart, Charles B. Phillips (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Letter to Col. Charles A. Lindberg re song written in his honor. Correspondence with M. Charles Louis Loretan re song on beekeeping - words and music included, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt re honey sent to him (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - John W. Moir, Edinburgh, Scotland re exchanges with Cornell Library of material on beekeeping (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - K.Y. Fay re Chinese beekeeping literature and material he supplied to beekeeping library, 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Imogene B. Woloctt (Mrs. Roger Wilcott) re proposed book on life of Charles Dadant (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Outline for courses in beekeeping, North Carolina State College, made by J.E. Eckert (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - C.B. Williams, letter re Braula Coeca in England (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Ing. Ctibor Blattny, Czechoslovakia - Correspondence and brief abstract of his work on artificial rearing of mites, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Arthur C. Miller re publication of pamphlet "The Wiley Honey Life", 1906 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Florence Naille, correspondence re preparation of biography of L.L. Langstroth. Mrs. H.R. Philbrick, Rev. Frederick B. Noss, E.R. Root (Box 3, Folder 47-48)
  - G.A. Rosch, correspondence beginning in 1927; letter from Frau Brubrun Rosch re fate of her husband (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Dr. L. Bahr re formation of an international society of bee-culture (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - O.E. Gallup, correspondence re Elisha Gallup (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mrs. W.Z. Hutchinson re books and a portrait presented to her by the beekeeping library (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mrs. W.Z. Lloyd re Peabody Honey Extractor donated to Cornell University (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - G.P. Putnam (publisher), letter re Gilman book "Practical Bee Breeding" (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Longmans, Green and Co. (publisher), letters re E.B. Wednore's book "A Manual of Beekeeping", 1932 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - N.G. Eremie re plan for adopting a standard bee hive for Romania, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Arthur C. Miller, correspondence re his beekeeping library and book plate for Charles C. Miller library (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - James G. Needham re work in beekeeping at Cornell University (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - C.C. Miller Memorial Library: its establishment and growth. C.P. Dadant, Chairman of Committee on Miller Memorial Library, J.G. Needham, H.G. Rowe, Gleanings in Bee Culture, E.R. Root, Mrs. Sidney J. Miller, E.G. Lestourgeon, Mgr. Texas Honey Producers Assn., Louis H. School, The Beekeepers' Item, H.F. Wilson, S.W. Beyer, 1920-30 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - War Effort of Entomologists, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 4-7)
    Letters and reports of Committee on Coordination of Entomology with the War Effort; report on Conference on War Problems in Biology and Agriculture; report on War Activities of Bureau of Entomology and Plant Quarantine; U.S. Dept. of Ag. Report on Ag. Production of 1943.
    Correspondence with the following: P.N. Annand, Chief Bureau of Ent., Washington, D.C.; Robert Griggs; C.E. Palm; Dept. of Entomology, Cornell University; Harry B. Weiss, President Am. Assn. Econ. Ent.; F.L. Campbell; C.H. Richardson; Charles P. Alexander, Pres. Ent. Soc. of Am.; F.C. Bishop, Chief Joint Committee on War-Work Training; C.E. Mickel, Ent. Soc. of America; E.O. Essig, professor of Entomology, Univ. of California; John S. Hauser; W.B. Herms, Univ. of California; Ernest N. Cory; H.A. Wallace, Sec., Dept. of Ag.; H.B. Hungerford, Univ. of Kansas; Harold D. Smith, Dir., Bureau of Budget; Avery S. Hoyt, U.S. Dept. of Ag.
  - Correspondence re honey grading - H.W. Samson, U.S. Bureau of Ag. Econ., E.P. Norgord, Dept. of Farms and Markets, Albany (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Crop Protection Committee reports and correspondence (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Correspondence with E.C. Stackman, Chairman; Robert F. Griggs, Chairman Div. of Biol. and Ag., Natl. Research Council; Major Gen. Lewis B. Hershey; Dr. J.G. Leach, Acting Chairman, War Emer. Committee; Harry B. Weiss; J.D. Walker, Chairman of Sub-committee on Seed Certification; Ross G. Harrison, Chairman, Natl. Research Council. Also, correspondence with Dr. Walter F. Loehwing and G.W. Keitt, Prof. of Plant Pathology, Univ. of Wisconsin
    Mimeo entitled "A Proposal re Ag. Services in Foreign Territories Occupied by American Troops."
    Report on meeting of Am. Phytopathological Society, Feb. 13-14, 1943. Report of Fungicide Sub-committee, War Emergency Committee, Am. Phytopathological Society. Memo on the War Problem of Manpower in Plant Pathology
  - Correspondence, review, and contract on W.F. Phillips' book "Beekeeping." L.H. Bailey, H.S. Latham, The Macmillan Co., E.A. Elder (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lloyd R. Watson, data on variation in tongue length of progeny of queenbees, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re patent assignment of Dyce Process to Cornell University; use of royalties; honey prices; building of apiary; complaints of liscenses. Elton J. Dyce, G.F. Rogalsky, Livingston Farrand, A.R. Mann (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Canadian patent in Dyce honey process; license agreement. J.B. Fairbairn, Deputy Min. of Ag., F.E. Millen, Ontario Ag. College, E.J. Dyce, Robert V. Morse, M.B. Gordon, Smart and Biggar (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Letters re review of Maeterlinck book reportedly by Mark Twain. Albert Bigelow Paine (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Letter from C.H. Lake and biog. note on him (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Coordination of entomology with war effort; occupational classification bulletin. Correspondence with Ernest N. Cory, A.G. Ruggles, Dr. Leonard Carmichael (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Reports and correspondence re activities of the special Committee on Entomological Work in the Dept. of Ag. and in the States (to consider impending reorganization of Dept. of Ag.) Ag. Appropiation. Dr. Lewis W. Douglass, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Interference of C.J. Bangham in securing patent on Dyce Process. Charles Bangham, R.A. Emerson, L.N. Simmons, E.J. Dyce, Robert V. Morse, J.B. Fairbairn (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Honey bottling business with Preserves and Honey, Inc.; honey experiments. E.R. Root, Huber H. Root (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re American Bee Journal's claim of priority on Dyce Process. M.G. Dandant, Am. Bee Journal, E.J. Dyce (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re Dyce Process patent and library of beekeeping literature at Cornell. R.F. Remer, Robert V. Morse, L.N. Simmons, Livingston Farrand, G.F. Rogalsky, E.J. Dyce (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re misunderstanding that arose over similarity in Dyce and Latham honey process. Allen Latham (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - F. Eric Miller re his hoped for graduate work, job possibilities (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - George W. Adams, letter re his beekeeping experiences (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - John H. Lovell re his book on honey plants and abstracting of honey plant literature (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Research Foundation vs. Sioux Honey Assn. Allan H. Treman, G.F. Rogalsky (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - M. l'Abbe A. Delaigues, request to bequeath his library to Cornell (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Feldmarscaaleutnant Alexander von Matyas re E.F. Phillips visit to Hungry (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dr, Hugo von Buttle-Reepen re translation of his pamphlet "Sin Bienen Reflexmachinen," by Mary Geisler, and financial aid given to him (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Alexander Bogdanoff re book on bee-hives and subject of bee-hives (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - F.W.L. Sladen, author of The Humble Bee, a book on queen rearing and other papers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence re application for British patent on Dyce Process and request for its revocation by New Zealand Honey Control Board. E.J. Dyce and Latham honey process. Allen Latham (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Superior Honey Co. application for license to manufacture honey by Dyce method; price ceilings. M.S. Stone, Superior Honey Co., L.N. Simmons, S.D. Redfield, Superior Honey Co., E.J. Dyce, Don H. Lee (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Samuel Cushman, letter requesting copies of his publications (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Confidential letter to editors of all bee journals re editorial policy of bee journals (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Other material
  - Photographs (none of Dyce Lab) (Box 5, Folder 13-18)
  - The Bee Man: Life and Letters of Everett Franklin Phillips by Mary Geisler Phillips, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Letter from L.L. Langstroth to "Ernest" and notes to Mr. Malin's letter to Langstroth, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Miscellany, including memos from 1904-1907 for which Mary Phillips used the blank side for translating beekeeping articles from German to English (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Letters
  - D.L. Adair, December 4, 1868 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Blumhof, August 21, 1868 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Blumhof (Box 5)
  - Samuel Wagner, January 24, 1869 (Box 5)
  - N.C. Mitchell, March 1, 1870 (Box 5)
  - Henry Alley, December 12, 1870 (Box 5)
  - Adam Grimm, June 25, 1871 (Box 5)
  - C. Cochran Jr., September 4, 1871 (Box 5)
  - H. Nesbit, March 20, 1872 (Box 5)
  - Elisha Gallup, March 23, 1872 (Box 5)
  - Frank Benton, March 25, 1872 (Box 5)
  - George. S. Wagner, August 7, 1872 (Box 5)
  - George S. Wagner, September 14, 1872 (Box 5)
  - L.L. Langstroth, March 22, 1873 (Box 5)
  - W.W. Cary, April 28, 1873 (Box 5)
  - T.G. Newman, February 18, 1874 (Box 5)
  - James Heddon (postcard), December 21, 1874 (Box 5)
  - J.L. Davis (postcard), July 2, 1875 (Box 5)
  - T.F. Bingham, October 17, 1878 (Box 5)
  - J.M. Davis, April 30, 1878 (Box 5)
  - Oscar Clute, June 7, 1878 (Box 5)
  - A.I. Root (postcard), August 7, 1878 (Box 5)
  - Dr. C.C. Miller (postcard), 1878 (Box 5)
  - Frances Dunham, October 2, 1878 (Box 5)
  - G.M. Doolittle (postcard), December 26, 1878 (Box 5)
  - Petition on adulteration, 1878 (Box 5)
  - A.J. Cook (postcard), January 10, 1878 (Box 5)
  - Julius Hoffman (postcard), January 11, 1878 (Box 5)
  - W.Z. Hutchinson (postcard), June 18, 1879 (Box 5)
  - L.L. Langstroth, January 5, 1880 (Box 5)
  - L.L. Langstroth, April 20, 1888 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Johannes Dzierzon (Box 5)
  - Japanese Fable (Box 5)
  - Phillips' Passport (Box 5)
  - Correspondence (in alphabetical order) concerning collection development efforts at expanding the Everett Phillips Beekeeping Library, 1947-1950 (Box 5)